Kishor Kumar Sridhar

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Graduate student in Information Systems with 3+ years of industry experience in data analytics, data science, business intelligence, client/stakeholder engagement, project management and database management. Proven experience in statistical analysis, implementing ML algorithms, handling Big Data using HDFS, and presenting compelling dashboards to support evidence-based decision-makings.

EDUCATION

Master of Information Systems, Minor in Statistics (STEM), Iowa State University, GPA – 3.75/4Nov. 2020B.E. in Electrical and Electronics, Anna University, India, GPA – 7.58/10May 2013

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming: R – tidyverse, ggplot2, leaflet; Python - numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, statsmodels; Git

Databases: MS – SQL Server, MySQL, MS-Access, Teradata, AWS Redshift

BI Tools: Power BI, Tableau, R Shiny, MS – Excel, DOMO, Alteryx

Statistics: ANOVA, Hypothesis testing, MLE, Time series forecasting, A/B testing

Bigdata: Hadoop, Spark, Pig, Hive, MapReduce, Impala, Kafka

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow May 2020 – Aug. 2020

Data Science for Public Good Fellowship, Ames, IA

- Led two Data Science projects to implement an end-to-end Data Science framework using statistical modeling and analyses
- Developed an R Shiny dashboard to improve public awareness of Iowa's resources related to mental and physical health, education, and childcare for evidence-based policy-making in substance abuse prevention, treatment, and recovery programs
- Acquired data through web-scraping, built data pipelines, assessed data governance, and spatially mapped county-level composite
 indicators of Social and Natural Assets related to upward economic mobility
- Communicated analytical findings to non-technical audience using R Shiny dashboard for assessing community well-being in Iowa
- Performed time series forecasting to estimate alcohol sales in Iowa and spatially segmented high-risk alcohol using population
- Created a prototype of an interactive dashboard that performs sentiment analysis (NLP) on generated transcripts from Hotlines to support improved customer service and auto-generate reports

Data Science Intern June 2018 – May 2020

Iowa Department of Transportation, Ames, IA

- Implemented time series forecasting using FB Prophet model to estimate customer wait-times for Live display on DOT website
- Performed hypothesis testing, statistical modeling on pavement conditions and created Power BI dashboards to recommend insights
- Applied topic modeling (NLP) on 10,000 public feedbacks to identify factors governing highway maintenance
- Used Python and Unix scripts to read and write on HDFS and analyzed high volume of data using Hadoop, Pig, Hive, and Spark
- Prepared over 4TB data for evaluation into Hadoop Clusters and reduced data storage by 75% using Spark by creating Parquet files
- Performed statistical analysis for identifying correlation between crash vs weather data and developed ML forecasting models
- Improved the performance of the application by 50% by transforming RDD to Spark DataFrames
- Designed and implemented a scalable solution for managing an immense amount of weather and crash data larger than 4TB
- Developed efficient SQL scripts for data cleansing, transformation and data modeling for ad-hoc analysis and reporting

Business Data Analyst Aug. 2016 – Oct. 2017

Torus, Chennai, India

- Automated insurance claims processing systems with integrated document management to reduce turn-around time by 30%
- Defined the scope of projects by translating requirements into Epics, User Stories and running Sprints with clear timeframes
- Assisted in planning, development, implementation of multivariate & A/B testing to improve conversion rate based on various KPIs

Programmer Analyst Feb. 2014 – July 2016

Infosys, Chennai, India

- Performed extensive data governance activities using Enablon EHS tool for a data migration project to modernize legacy systems
- Improved database performance by reducing query execution time by 50% using efficient SOL queries and stored procedures
- Communicated as a liaison between the client and technical team to deliver key business solutions using Agile methodologies
- Leveraged Microsoft SSIS to transform data for ETL processes; coordinated with QA teams to execute UAT cycles

LEADERSHIP